# Tim Dosé

# UX Designer/Developer

My passion is **cross-discipline collaboration** that results in **functional design**, improvement in a human's experience of a product or service, and increases in meaningful business metrics. I can design, develop, and/or manage teams.

timdose@gmail.com 917-575-5359 timdose.com/ux

# Work Experience

## Yodle

#### 2012-Present

#### User Experience Manager

- Led user testing and A/B testing on Yodle.com which has raised web conversion 30%.
- Led the re-design and development of Yodle's newest CMS, powering over 10,000 of Yodle's client sites. Led to a 17% increase in client satisfaction and a 60% improvement in setup time.
- Pioneered Lean processes in conjuction with the Marketing team.
- Managed and mentored Interaction Designers, Visual Designers, and Front End Developers

### Lead UX Front Developer

- Led the design and development for over 100 templates for Yodle's previous CMS.
- Coordinated with Product Management and Client Services to prioritize template coverage needs based on sales velocity.

## 2011-2012 UX Front End Developer

- Increased template quality and development speed by standardizing design and dev processes.
- Designed and developed dozens of web templates.

#### 2010-2011 Web Designer/Developer

- Created client sites and pioneered design/development techniques on newly built in-house CMS.
- Trained and supported Client Service Reps on in-house CMS.
- Mentored and trained fellow developers in best practices, including JavaScript and Firebug.

## Freelance

#### 2003-2010 Web Designer/Developer

- Designed and developed user-customizable websites for artists and writers.
- Designed and built lightweight CMS for clients to upload, edit, and maintain their own content.

## Rebel Monkey Games

### 2007-2009

### Lead Game Artist/Technical Artist

- Created 2D and 3D character and background art for Flash-based multiplayer casual games.
- Designed and developed an animated avatar system for users to customize their in-game characters along 20+ parameters.
- Created the front end for the game's virtual clothing store.
- Led a small team of art and development interns.
- Worked closely with engineers and the other artists to create pipelines for game assets.

# Lindgren & Smith, Inc.

## 2001-2007 IT Specialist

- Developed and maintained multiple company websites.
- Created custom database solution to track clients, projects, and invoices.
- Built asset management database to catalog thousands of images by 40+ artists.
- Hired and managed part-time workers and interns.

## Skills

## Methodologies & Processes

- Agile UX, Lean UX
- · Usability Testing
- A/B Testing
- · Process Flows, Wireframing
- · Personas, Card Sorting
- · Responsive Design
- Test-Driven Development
- · Unit Testing, E2E Testing

## **Technologies**

- HTML/HTML5
- · CSS/CSS3, LESS
- Javascript, PHP, Python
- · MySQL, PostgreSQL
- jQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS
- · ExpressJS, Flash, CherryPy
- · Webdriver, Selenium

### Tools

- · Adobe Creative Suite, OmniGraffle
- Git, Mercurial, SVN
- Jira, Trello
- ¡Query, Bootstrap, AngularJS
- · ExpressJS, Flash, CherryPy
- · Maya, ads Max, Blender, zBrush

## Education

• BFA in Illustration, Syracuse University